<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-04T10:16:29+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/</id><title type="html">A Voice For Leith Hill</title><subtitle>Non-party political community group committed to raising awareness and protesting against the proposed oil exploration at Leith Hill</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Current Status and Timelines</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/02/timelines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Current Status and Timelines" /><published>2017-03-02T12:50:24+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-02T12:50:24+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/02/timelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/02/timelines/">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Surrey County Council refused permission for a planning application to explore for oil and gas at Leith Hill. The decision was appealed, and the subsequent public inquiry again rejected permission. That decision was then challenged in the High Court, which found favour with the applicant resulting in a second public inquiry. This unfortunately coincided with a change in the planning regulations, and as a result the government planning inspectorate decided to grant permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Government Planning Inspectorate&lt;/b&gt;'s decision (ref: APP/B3600/A/11/2166561) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://acp.planninginspectorate.gov.uk/ViewCase.aspx?caseid=2166561&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;hr class=&quot;spacer&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Environment Agency Permit Applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EA's permit application register is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/environmental-permitting-notices-of-applications-made&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing has been submitted to them so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;spacer&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Surrey County Council Planning Applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrey County Council planning application register is &lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planapplist.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The full list of required submissions (some of which, e.g. traffic management plan, are still pending) can be found listed in the approval conditions of planning inspectorate's decision, linked above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Ref&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Action Required&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0001&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2017/0001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1.1 metre high reptile fence&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Formal public consultation period is 03/03/2017 - 27/03/2017&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0232&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0232*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Perimeter security fencing (identical to 2016/0170, but now extended for 52 weeks)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Unconfirmed so far by SCC whether this will have a separate formal public consultation period&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0194&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0194&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Landscape and Restoration Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Compulsory public consultation finished; pending decision by Delegated Powers&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0193&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0193&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Pre and post development condition survey&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Planning Committee 22/02/2017&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0170&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0170*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Perimeter security fencing (see also 2016/0232 above)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;decision by Planning Committee: provisionally scheduled for March 2017 meeting&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;TBD (attendance at planning hearing)&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0151&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0151&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Groundwater and Surface Water Baseline Quality and Monitoring&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Delegated Powers 21/10/2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0132&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0132&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Ecological Monitoring and Management Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Compulsory public consultation finished; pending decision by Delegated Powers&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0104&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0104&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Light Management Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Planning Committee 07/12/2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0103&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Dust Suppression Scheme&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Delegated Powers 08/12/2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* asterisked items denote new, additional planning applications rather than submissions concerning the fulfillment (or &quot;discharge&quot;) of the conditions previously specified by the planning inspectorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction In 2011, Surrey County Council refused permission for a planning application to explore for oil and gas at Leith Hill. The decision was appealed, and the subsequent public inquiry again rejected permission. That decision was then challenged in the High Court, which found favour with the applicant resulting in a second public inquiry. This unfortunately coincided with a change in the planning regulations, and as a result the government planning inspectorate decided to grant permission. The Government Planning Inspectorate's decision (ref: APP/B3600/A/11/2166561) is here. Environment Agency Permit Applications The EA's permit application register is here. Nothing has been submitted to them so far. Surrey County Council Planning Applications Surrey County Council planning application register is here. The full list of required submissions (some of which, e.g. traffic management plan, are still pending) can be found listed in the approval conditions of planning inspectorate's decision, linked above. Ref Title Status Action Required 2017/0001 1.1 metre high reptile fence Formal public consultation period is 03/03/2017 - 27/03/2017 Yes 2016/0232* Perimeter security fencing (identical to 2016/0170, but now extended for 52 weeks) Unconfirmed so far by SCC whether this will have a separate formal public consultation period Objections may still be submitted for consideration 2016/0194 Landscape and Restoration Plan Compulsory public consultation finished; pending decision by Delegated Powers Objections may still be submitted for consideration 2016/0193 Pre and post development condition survey Approved by Planning Committee 22/02/2017 Yes 2016/0170* Perimeter security fencing (see also 2016/0232 above) decision by Planning Committee: provisionally scheduled for March 2017 meeting TBD (attendance at planning hearing) 2016/0151 Groundwater and Surface Water Baseline Quality and Monitoring Approved by Delegated Powers 21/10/2016 2016/0132 Ecological Monitoring and Management Plan Compulsory public consultation finished; pending decision by Delegated Powers Objections may still be submitted for consideration 2016/0104 Light Management Plan Approved by Planning Committee 07/12/2016 2016/0103 Dust Suppression Scheme Approved by Delegated Powers 08/12/2016 * asterisked items denote new, additional planning applications rather than submissions concerning the fulfillment (or &quot;discharge&quot;) of the conditions previously specified by the planning inspectorate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High Street Stall - 4th March</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/01/stall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Street Stall - 4th March" /><published>2017-03-01T11:12:04+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-01T11:12:04+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/01/stall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/01/stall/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/stall.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're going to be out on the high street again this Saturday morning (4th March, from 9:30am) at our usual spot outside Oxfam. Please drop by to say hello, pick up a leaflet, or to find out more about the current status of the campaign! Hope to see you there...&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Surrey Slings Leith Hill Celebration Walk</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/12/03/leith-hill-walk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surrey Slings Leith Hill Celebration Walk" /><published>2016-12-03T00:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-03T00:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/12/03/leith-hill-walk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/12/03/leith-hill-walk/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/surrey-slings-walk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surrey Slings Leith Hill Celebration Walk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Meeting places for the Leith Hill Celebration Walk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St Joseph's Church, Falkland Grove, Dorking, RH4 3DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Cyclists meeting at 10.30am to cycle up Coldharbour Lane and walk to the tower.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starveall Car Park, Leith Hill Rd, Dorking, RH5 6LU:&lt;/strong&gt; A family friendly route, with walkers meeting at 10.15am and departing at 10.30am. It is suitable for small children, buggies and older people looking for a gentle walk.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday Street, Dorking, RH5 6JR:&lt;/strong&gt; Walkers are meeting at 10.30am for a 10.45am start. The route is suitable for adults and capable walkers.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windy Gap Car Park, Abinger Road, Dorking, RH5 6LX:&lt;/strong&gt; A steep ascent to the tower that is expected to take around 40 minutes to complete.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landslip Car Park, Abinger Road, Dorking, RH5 6HG:&lt;/strong&gt; A short, steep climb to the top of the hill that should take around 45 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rhodedenron Wood Car Park, Dorking, RH5 6LU:&lt;/strong&gt; A longer route from Leith Hill Place's car park with some steep sections.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The Facebook event details are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/333484617025339/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trees In The Early Morning</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trees In The Early Morning" /><published>2016-09-02T08:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T08:10:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;For me, trees have always been the most penetrating preachers. I revere them when they live in tribes and families, in forests and groves. And even more I revere them when they stand alone. They are like lonely persons. Not like hermits who have stolen away out of some weakness, but like great, solitary men, like Beethoven and Nietzsche. In their highest boughs the world rustles, their roots rest in infinity; but they do not lose themselves there, they struggle with all the force of their lives for one thing only: to fulfil themselves according to their own laws, to build up their own form, to represent themselves. Nothing is holier, nothing is more exemplary than a beautiful, strong tree. When a tree is cut down and reveals its naked death-wound to the sun, one can read its whole history in the luminous, inscribed disk of its trunk: in the rings of its years, its scars, all the struggle, all the suffering, all the sickness, all the happiness and prosperity stand truly written, the narrow years and the luxurious years, the attacks withstood, the storms endured. And every young farmboy knows that the hardest and noblest wood has the narrowest rings, that high on the mountains and in continuing danger the most indestructible, the strongest, the ideal trees grow.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Trees are sanctuaries. Whoever knows how to speak to them, whoever knows how to listen to them, can learn the truth. They do not preach learning and precepts, they preach, undeterred by particulars, the ancient law of life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A tree says: A kernel is hidden in me, a spark, a thought, I am life from eternal life. The attempt and the risk that the eternal mother took with me is unique, unique the form and veins of my skin, unique the smallest play of leaves in my branches and the smallest scar on my bark. I was made to form and reveal the eternal in my smallest special detail.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A tree says: My strength is trust. I know nothing about my fathers, I know nothing about the thousand children that every year spring out of me. I live out the secret of my seed to the very end, and I care for nothing else. I trust that God is in me. I trust that my labor is holy. Out of this trust I live.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When we are stricken and cannot bear our lives any longer, then a tree has something to say to us: Be still! Be still! Look at me! Life is not easy, life is not difficult. Those are childish thoughts. Let God speak within you, and your thoughts will grow silent. You are anxious because your path leads away from mother and home. But every step and every day lead you back again to the mother. Home is neither here nor there. Home is within you, or home is nowhere at all.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A longing to wander tears my heart when I hear trees rustling in the wind at evening. If one listens to them silently for a long time, this longing reveals its kernel, its meaning. It is not so much a matter of escaping from one's suffering, though it may seem to be so. It is a longing for home, for a memory of the mother, for new metaphors for life. It leads home. Every path leads homeward, every step is birth, every step is death, every grave is mother.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So the tree rustles in the evening, when we stand uneasy before our own childish thoughts: Trees have long thoughts, long-breathing and restful, just as they have longer lives than ours. They are wiser than we are, as long as we do not listen to them. But when we have learned how to listen to trees, then the brevity and the quickness and the childlike hastiness of our thoughts achieve an incomparable joy. Whoever has learned how to listen to trees no longer wants to be a tree. He wants to be nothing except what he is. That is home. That is happiness.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

- Herman Hesse, Wandering (1915)

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the glorious trees which are most at risk of direct damage at the proposed drilling site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040312-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040311-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040306-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040305-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040304-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">&quot;For me, trees have always been the most penetrating preachers. I revere them when they live in tribes and families, in forests and groves. And even more I revere them when they stand alone. They are like lonely persons. Not like hermits who have stolen away out of some weakness, but like great, solitary men, like Beethoven and Nietzsche. In their highest boughs the world rustles, their roots rest in infinity; but they do not lose themselves there, they struggle with all the force of their lives for one thing only: to fulfil themselves according to their own laws, to build up their own form, to represent themselves. Nothing is holier, nothing is more exemplary than a beautiful, strong tree. When a tree is cut down and reveals its naked death-wound to the sun, one can read its whole history in the luminous, inscribed disk of its trunk: in the rings of its years, its scars, all the struggle, all the suffering, all the sickness, all the happiness and prosperity stand truly written, the narrow years and the luxurious years, the attacks withstood, the storms endured. And every young farmboy knows that the hardest and noblest wood has the narrowest rings, that high on the mountains and in continuing danger the most indestructible, the strongest, the ideal trees grow. Trees are sanctuaries. Whoever knows how to speak to them, whoever knows how to listen to them, can learn the truth. They do not preach learning and precepts, they preach, undeterred by particulars, the ancient law of life. A tree says: A kernel is hidden in me, a spark, a thought, I am life from eternal life. The attempt and the risk that the eternal mother took with me is unique, unique the form and veins of my skin, unique the smallest play of leaves in my branches and the smallest scar on my bark. I was made to form and reveal the eternal in my smallest special detail. A tree says: My strength is trust. I know nothing about my fathers, I know nothing about the thousand children that every year spring out of me. I live out the secret of my seed to the very end, and I care for nothing else. I trust that God is in me. I trust that my labor is holy. Out of this trust I live. When we are stricken and cannot bear our lives any longer, then a tree has something to say to us: Be still! Be still! Look at me! Life is not easy, life is not difficult. Those are childish thoughts. Let God speak within you, and your thoughts will grow silent. You are anxious because your path leads away from mother and home. But every step and every day lead you back again to the mother. Home is neither here nor there. Home is within you, or home is nowhere at all. A longing to wander tears my heart when I hear trees rustling in the wind at evening. If one listens to them silently for a long time, this longing reveals its kernel, its meaning. It is not so much a matter of escaping from one's suffering, though it may seem to be so. It is a longing for home, for a memory of the mother, for new metaphors for life. It leads home. Every path leads homeward, every step is birth, every step is death, every grave is mother. So the tree rustles in the evening, when we stand uneasy before our own childish thoughts: Trees have long thoughts, long-breathing and restful, just as they have longer lives than ours. They are wiser than we are, as long as we do not listen to them. But when we have learned how to listen to trees, then the brevity and the quickness and the childlike hastiness of our thoughts achieve an incomparable joy. Whoever has learned how to listen to trees no longer wants to be a tree. He wants to be nothing except what he is. That is home. That is happiness.&quot;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leith Hill Place - Short Film</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leith Hill Place - Short Film" /><published>2016-08-14T00:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-14T00:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place/">&lt;div id=&quot;avplayer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  // Load the IFrame Player API code asynchronously.
  var tag = document.createElement('script');
  tag.src = &quot;https://www.youtube.com/player_api&quot;;
  var firstScriptTag = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0];
  firstScriptTag.parentNode.insertBefore(tag, firstScriptTag);

  // Replace the 'ytplayer' element with an &lt;iframe&gt; and
  // YouTube player after the API code downloads.
  var player;
  function onYouTubePlayerAPIReady() {
    player = new YT.Player('avplayer', {
      height: '315',
      width: '560',
      videoId: 'j7m4eS60Dnk'
    });
  }
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leith Hill Place</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leith Hill Place" /><published>2016-07-21T22:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-21T22:20:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/VFLH-NT-VERSION14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bring a Picnic Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Voice For Leith Hill</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/01/about-v4lh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Voice For Leith Hill" /><published>2016-07-01T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-01T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/01/about-v4lh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/01/about-v4lh/">&lt;p&gt;A Voice For Leith Hill (AVFLH) are a group of local artists, musicians and environmentalists who joined together to protest peacefully and raise awareness concerning the planned oil drilling on Leith Hill due to start later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campaign originated at a picnic event on the planned drilling site in Bury Hill Woods in the autumn of 2015, where participants decided on a plan of peaceful action through a series of art exhibitions and concerts aimed at raising awareness about the pending senseless destruction of one of the South of England's most beautiful and cherished natural habitats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A travelling art exhibition celebrating the beauty of Leith Hill and highlighting the wildlife under threat commenced at The Star, Dorking in January 2016 where it remained until end of March. There was a successful opening event with local bands, guest speakers and many signatures added to our petition. During this time AVFLH also ran a stall in Dorking High Street with a big live street art demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April the exhibition was warmly welcomed at the newly refurbished Plough Inn, Coldharbour with a jam-packed opening event including the village bands, A Voice For Leith Hill musicians and speakers, a speech from the LHAG chairman and a talk about the ecology under threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 6th August to 30th October 2016, the exhibition then moved to Leith Hill Place. On Saturday 13th August there was a family picnoic launch event that included live music, art activities and further talks. The following footage was taken during that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;avplayer&quot; class=&quot;avplayer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  // Load the IFrame Player API code asynchronously.
  var tag = document.createElement('script');
  tag.src = &quot;https://www.youtube.com/player_api&quot;;
  var firstScriptTag = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0];
  firstScriptTag.parentNode.insertBefore(tag, firstScriptTag);

  // Replace the 'ytplayer' element with an &lt;iframe&gt; and
  // YouTube player after the API code downloads.
  var player;
  function onYouTubePlayerAPIReady() {
    player = new YT.Player('avplayer', {
      height: '315',
      width: '560',
      videoId: 'j7m4eS60Dnk'
    });
  }
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">A Voice For Leith Hill (AVFLH) are a group of local artists, musicians and environmentalists who joined together to protest peacefully and raise awareness concerning the planned oil drilling on Leith Hill due to start later this year. The campaign originated at a picnic event on the planned drilling site in Bury Hill Woods in the autumn of 2015, where participants decided on a plan of peaceful action through a series of art exhibitions and concerts aimed at raising awareness about the pending senseless destruction of one of the South of England's most beautiful and cherished natural habitats. A travelling art exhibition celebrating the beauty of Leith Hill and highlighting the wildlife under threat commenced at The Star, Dorking in January 2016 where it remained until end of March. There was a successful opening event with local bands, guest speakers and many signatures added to our petition. During this time AVFLH also ran a stall in Dorking High Street with a big live street art demonstration. In April the exhibition was warmly welcomed at the newly refurbished Plough Inn, Coldharbour with a jam-packed opening event including the village bands, A Voice For Leith Hill musicians and speakers, a speech from the LHAG chairman and a talk about the ecology under threat. From 6th August to 30th October 2016, the exhibition then moved to Leith Hill Place. On Saturday 13th August there was a family picnoic launch event that included live music, art activities and further talks. The following footage was taken during that day.</summary></entry></feed>