<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-24T21:45:51+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/</id><title type="html">A Voice For Leith Hill</title><subtitle>Non-party political community group committed to raising awareness and protesting against the proposed oil exploration at Leith Hill</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Injunction defense crowdfunder launch</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/04/23/injunction-crowdfunder/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Injunction defense crowdfunder launch" /><published>2018-04-23T13:01:32+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-23T13:01:32+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/04/23/injunction-crowdfunder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/04/23/injunction-crowdfunder/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;crowdfunder-to-defend-against-ukog-injunction-goes-live&quot;&gt;Crowdfunder to defend against UKOG injunction goes live&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weald Action Group, and the six local campaigners who are challenging the UK Oil and Gas (UKOG) injunction, have launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdjustice.com/case/oppressive-oil-injunction&quot;&gt;their crowdfunder&lt;/a&gt;  today to pay for their legal costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann, Sue, Natasha, Constance, Vicki and Jacqui have courageously stepped forward to fight this High Court injunction.  This injunction could stop the right to peaceful protest and prevent local people raising awareness of the new risky methods of unconventional oil and gas drilling and the industrialisation of our beautiful countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdjustice.com/case/oppressive-oil-injunction&quot;&gt;Can you please pledge to support them?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; It doesn’t matter as to the amount. EVERY BIT HELPS!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/injunction-injustice-main.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These type of injunctions are draconian in its chilling effect, and counter to the right to assembly and the right to freedom of expression.  There is already criminal law to deal with any unlawful activities, and this injunction should have no part in defining what is legal and what is not. It is a blatant attack on our human rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this injunction is granted it could also serve as a precedent for other oil and companies here and around the country. It should be fiercely resisted and we need to raise funds for our legal costs to fight this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do share on your social media and/or forward this email to your friends. It helps SO much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the shareable Facebook post.  Also click on this search for #injunctioninjustice on Twitter to retweet or create your own using the hashtag #injunctioninjustice and the crowdfunder link&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are all in this together and we can’t do any of this without your support. So &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdjustice.com/case/oppressive-oil-injunction&quot;&gt;please donate now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and help to stop this injunction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DrillorDrop articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/03/06/ukog-seeks-injunction-to-ban-any-legal-protest-that-damagess-its-business/&quot;&gt;6th March report&lt;/a&gt; - UKOG seeks injunction to ban protests that aim to damage its business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/03/15/campaigners-to-challenge-oil-company-at-high-court-over-protest-injunction/&quot;&gt;15th March report&lt;/a&gt; - Campaigners to challenge oil company at High Court over protest injunction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/03/17/human-rights-campaigner-urges-oil-company-to-drop-high-court-bid-for-injunction/&quot;&gt;17th March report&lt;/a&gt; - Human rights campaigner urges oil company to drop High Court bid for injunction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/03/19/shires-of-england-rise-up-as-oil-company-ukog-seeks-high-court-injunction-against-protests/&quot;&gt;19th March report&lt;/a&gt; - “Shires of England rise up” as oil company UKOG seeks High Court injunction against protests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/03/19/court-adjourns-decision-on-wide-ranging-injunction-against-protests-at-ukog-oil-drilling-sites/&quot;&gt;19th March report&lt;/a&gt; - Court adjourns decision on “wide-ranging” injunction against protests at UKOG oil drilling sites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/04/05/oil-company-withdraws-key-clauses-in-protest-injunction/&quot;&gt;5th April report&lt;/a&gt; - Oil company withdraws key clauses in protest injunction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Crowdfunder to defend against UKOG injunction goes live</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">David Smythe EA report now submitted</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/04/03/prof-smythe-report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="David Smythe EA report now submitted" /><published>2018-04-03T22:22:35+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-03T22:22:35+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/04/03/prof-smythe-report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/04/03/prof-smythe-report/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;professor-david-smythes-report-about-the-leith-hill-drill-site&quot;&gt;Professor David Smythe’s report about the Leith Hill drill site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am led to the inescapable conclusion that the Applicant has a poor understanding of the geology, and of the technical problems that it is likely to encounter in drilling. In turn, its understanding of the hydrogeology is seriously defective. In consequence there is a serious and unacceptable risk that the drinking water aquifers in the district may be contaminated by the Applicant’s proposed activities, both in the short term and in the long term. The EA should refuse the present application.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Smythe’s report for AVFLH to the Environment Agency is a 57 page full technical analysis that will enable the EA reach an informed decision on Europa’s Permit application. &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/Smythe-EA-Europa-Consultation-Submission-v1_3r.pdf&quot;&gt;You can download it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please also see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/voiceforleithhill&quot;&gt;our JustGiving crowdfunding page&lt;/a&gt;. We now just need to find the final £200!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Professor David Smythe’s report about the Leith Hill drill site</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Video of Prof David Smythe lecture</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/03/23/prof-smythe-lecture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Video of Prof David Smythe lecture" /><published>2018-03-23T20:24:35+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-23T20:24:35+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/03/23/prof-smythe-lecture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/03/23/prof-smythe-lecture/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;professor-david-smythes-talk-about-the-leith-hill-drill-site&quot;&gt;Professor David Smythe’s talk about the Leith Hill drill site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Smythe (Emeritus Professor of Geophysics, University of Glasgow) visited Dorking to object to the Environment Agency granting a permit to drill the exploratory borehole through a principal aquifer. His talk at the Friends Meeting House clearly explains the underlying dangers, what unconventional extraction is, and why it doesn’t add up. While the talk focusses on Leith Hill, Professor Smythe refers to examples from sites across England, drawing on his academic background and his professional experience of working both at the British Geological Survey, and as a former consultant to the conventional oil industry on drill site selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;854&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hxoBMzMUo_c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Professor David Smythe’s talk about the Leith Hill drill site</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Environment Agency Consultation Guidance</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/03/23/ea-guidance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Environment Agency Consultation Guidance" /><published>2018-03-23T19:13:35+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-23T19:13:35+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/03/23/ea-guidance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/03/23/ea-guidance/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;environment-agency-consultation-guidance&quot;&gt;Environment Agency Consultation Guidance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Environment Agency (EA) say they are “minded to grant” Europa’s application to drill at Leith Hill, including the use of a 15% acid solution. This would be a huge mistake. The intended drill site is above a principal aquifer which feeds into Pipp Brook, local springs and the water supply for homes in Leatherhead, Dorking and surrounding villages, and is in a highly faulted area, like much of the UK. If the well leaks, either immediately or in the future, the aquifer could be irreparably contaminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact the EA to state using your own words one or more of the points below, and to demand that they act with proper caution and REJECT Europa’s application. Objections can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://consult.environment-agency.gov.uk/psc/rh6-6hn-europa-oil-and-gas-limited/consultation/intro/&quot;&gt;submitted online here&lt;/a&gt; until 29th March 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Smythe, Emeritus Professor of Geophysics, University of Glasgow is submitting a technical objection on behalf of A Voice For Leith Hill. However the number of objections will also count so you are encouraged to make your own and add that you support Professor Smythe’s submission, if you do. See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/voiceforleithhill&quot;&gt;our JustGiving crowdfunding page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The failure to apply the precautionary principle in assessing this permit application is a gross failure of risk management. Risk management without the precautionary principle is essentially simple gambling. That might arguably be acceptable in certain scenarios where the downside impact is low and the potential reward is high. In this instance however, the exact converse is true. The downside impact is the long-term contamination of the aquifer that supplies 70,000 homes across Dorking and Leatherhead. The potential reward is alleged to be increased energy security for the UK, however this is an energy source that according to the Paris Climate Accord we already have five times more of than we can ever safely burn if we are to avoid catastrophic climate change. What security is there in an energy source we can’t use? Surely any sane argument for energy security would be based on renewables which could serve us safely for many decades to come?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Europa’s financial position left them 12 months ago with ‘Cash at Bank’ of £1.4m and an accumulated deficit of £16.6m. Who ends up paying for the clean up if Europa Oil and Gas contaminates our water? What is the extent and terms of their public liability and professional indemnity insurance? If the company ceases trading are their insurance policies immediately invalidated?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Envireau Water’s work at Markwell’s Wood has already been comprehensively discredited by independent hydrologists, following which that site is now subject to an enforcement order that it be restored to its natural state. Why is their analysis at Leith Hill still being given credence, especially given the obvious conflict of interest created by them being paid by the drilling operator? Their risk assessment is based on an overly simplistic site model: e.g. it doesn’t deal with the connection between the Pipp Brook and the aquifer, the effect of near surface faults on groundwater flow or the effect of seasonal and annual water table level variations on groundwater flow. What are the risks in drilling through the heavily faulted geology that runs under watercourses which end up in our water resources? Contamination is known to travel up faults into an aquifer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Industry studies show that five to seven per cent of all new oil and gas wells leak. As wells age, the percentage of leakers can increase to 30 or 50 per cent. The most susceptible remain “deviated” or horizontal wells like the one being proposed here. SES Water objected to the drill plans on the basis that “the proposed exploratory well will penetrate the lower greensand aquifer in relatively close proximity to our Dorking abstraction source. We are concerned that, in the event of a leak or a spill, the proposed mitigation measures will not guarantee the aquifer’s protection.” SES Water have no vested political or economic interests in this proposal. Why were the objections of their unbiased, independent experts not heeded?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Europa were granted conditional permission to conduct exploratory drilling by the planning inspectorate on the basis that the drilling operation would be conventional. As a result, the permit wording should preclude the use of all stimulation techniques, not just hydraulic stimulation. The use of acids to stimulate oil flow is not a conventional technique. Although 7.5% acid washes are used in conventional wells, use of higher concentrations of Hydrochoric acid at the high ambient temperatures of the target formation and at high pressure is not a bore washing technique, it is the unconventional technique known as acidisation and is akin to hydraulic fracturing.   N.B. Any reservoir with a permeability of less than 0.1 mD is by scientific definition unconventional and so will require stimulation. The Kimmeridge Clay “limestone” formations have a permeability of between 0.005 and 0.03mD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Europa are claiming that “all of the dilute acid solution will return to the surface once it has reacted”. However, at Broadford Bridge in West Sussex, operator UKOG (also the largest financial interest in Europa’s project) have &lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2018/02/20/50m-wiped-off-ukog-on-news-of-possible-formation-damage-at-broadford-bridge-oil-well/&quot;&gt;just had to announce serious problems with their oil retrieval&lt;/a&gt; - the liquid they are retrieving contains a large quantity of acid which remained underground from historic acid washes. This casts serious doubt on claims that all of the solution will be retrieved here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hundreds of chemicals including a 15% hydrochloric acid solution will be used at the site. Why is a Groundwater Activity Permit is not required? The EA claim to have assessed the chemicals in the products that Europa want to use, and consider them not to present a risk that would make a Groundwater Activity Permit necessary. There is an inventory of hundreds of chemicals listed in the waste management plan. Is there peer reviewed evidence that each of these chemicals is safe to use in this type of drilling operation? If not the precautionary principle should be applied - our drinking water should not be put at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What will happen to the highly saline produced water and backwash from this operation. This typically also includes reaction products of injection chemicals and the formation rocks, and substances released or leached out from the formation, including salts, heavy metals and Naturally Occurring Radioactive Materials (NORMS). What volumes are currently forecast? There are no licensed facilities for handling this type of waste in southern England. Where will it go? How can an ecologically rich Area of Outstanding Natural Beauty be considered appropriate for the safe management and transport of naturally occurring radioactive materials (NORMs)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waste gas arising from testing will be flared using a shrouded flare. The assessment of the flare’s safety is based on a computer simulation which may be inaccurate because new research shows methane and ethane emissions associated with oil &amp;amp; gas extraction are higher than previously thought. This is particularly the case for the Bakken Shale in the US, which has been compared by the industry in the UK to the Weald. At UKOG’s site at Horse Hill near Horley, when flow testing was carried out, residents complained of headaches &amp;amp; respiratory problems. The assessment contains no information about the effect of the flare and fugitive gas emissions on human health. Given the reports from Horse Hill, and the information about fugitive emissions from the Bakken Shale and its similarity to the target formation, a more precautionary approach should be taken. The assessment makes no mention of the protest camp which is directly opposite the site and the effect on the health of the residents &amp;amp; visitors there. Special consideration is given to the effect Nitrogen Oxide emissions on a nearby Site of Special Scientific Interest, where ‘there is a potential exceedance of the 24 hour critical level for NOx (Nitrogen Oxide)’ - why should the same consideration not be extended to the entire local area, which equally contains older native woodland (e.g. the row of old oak trees which starts near the entrance). The proposed drill site and surrounding area is a haven for protected fauna species such as hazel dormice, nightjar, cuckoo, tree sparrow and song thrush.     &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constant monitoring of the efficiency of the flare is absolutely vital. If the flare efficiency falls below 95% then the flare will start to emit serious amounts of toxins, which will be transported on the prevailing wind towards Dorking. These include:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sulphur dioxide (SO2): At room temperature, sulphur dioxide is a non-flammable, colourless gas with a very strong, pungent odour and is heavier than air. Inhalation is the major route of exposure to sulphur dioxide. Most exposures are due to air pollution, and this has both short-term and chronic health consequences for people with lung disease. Inhaled sulphur dioxide readily reacts with the moisture of mucous membranes to form sulphurous acid (H2SO3), which is a severe irritant. People with asthma can experience increased airway resistance with sulphur dioxide concentrations of less than 125micrograms/m3 when exercising.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Polyaromatic hydrocarbons: Polyaromatic hydrocarbons are by-products arising from incomplete combustion of organic matter that are frequently released into our environment. They are produced in flares. Many polyaromatic hydrocarbons are strong carcinogens and have been linked to increased incidences of various types of cancer in humans for which there is no known safe threshold concentration or exposure time.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Particulate matter (PM): Nano-sized soot particles are generated in the flare which are detrimental to public health. Further air dispersion calculations of particulate matter (PM) generation are necessary, and the results should be added to emissions predicted from generators and traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dioxins Can the operator please provide information on expected dioxin levels in the flare gas? Dioxins are formed when incinerating chlorine-containing organic substances. Dioxins are very toxic and known human carcinogens and endocrine disruptors. A study conducted in the Netherlands reports the presence of dioxins in flared landfill gas, biogas and chlorine containing industrial gas. (National Institute of Public Health and Environmental Protection &amp;amp; Netherlands Organization for Applied Scientific Research, Report 770501018, Emissions of Dioxins in the Netherlands, February 1994). The dioxin levels of the flare gas should be monitored continuously, and contingency plans should be put in place should dioxins be detected in the flare gas.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volatile organic and inorganic chemicals and synergy of emissions. Workers and residents near to the flare will be exposed to benzene, ethylbenzene, xylene, toluene, pyrene, benzanthracene, anthracene, NOx, sulphur dioxide, carbon monoxide, radon, soot and many other combustion emissions. The risk of simultaneous exposure to such a cocktail of chemicals is completely unknown.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Environment Agency Consultation Guidance</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Petition nears 100,000 signatures</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/25/petition-water-supply/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Petition nears 100,000 signatures" /><published>2018-02-25T22:13:56+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-25T22:13:56+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/25/petition-water-supply</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/25/petition-water-supply/">&lt;h2&gt;Petition against risk to water supply nears 100,000 signatures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A petition aimed at demonstrating serious fears about the risk to local water supplies from oil drilling on Leith Hill is close to hundred thousand signatures. The petition, hosted by 38 Degrees, which is addressed to the Environment Agency (EA) titled ‘Don't risk water pollution from oil drilling on Leith Hill’ has been signed by over ninety-one thousand people, with more being added by the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organisers of the petition will be officially handing it in on Thursday 1 March at 6:30pm during a public consultation at the Dorking Halls, where residents have been invited to talk to EA representatives about how they will regulate the proposed oil and gas activities on Leith Hill in Surrey. The site is within an officially designated area of outstanding natural beauty (AONB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local resident who started the petition said, “We are encouraged that so many people agree the water pollution risks from oil drilling using acid and other chemicals are unacceptable. We call on the Environment Agency to act on our concerns by rejecting this application. Short term oil extraction is increasingly being prioritised by our Government over the protection of our water resource. Water will ultimately be much more valuable and important to our Nation than oil. It's short term thinking at it's worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Water is both a vital natural resource and a heritage, which must be protected, defended and treated as such. We would like to invite any local people who have concerns over the safety of our water due to the proposed acidisation drilling process, to join us in handing in this petition. We hope it makes a difference to the EA’s decision”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concerns were initially sparked when Sutton and East Surrey Water (SESW) spoke out during the planning appeal process against Europa’s plans, stating that an accidental spill or leak could contaminate the aquifer used for public water supply. Lester Sonden, then director of SESW, said he was concerned about the potential for long-term contamination of water sources. He said “Our objection to drilling in this location is that it will increase the risk of polluting the aquifer that is used for public water supply. Besides the risk of contaminating our borehole sources at Dorking, there is also a risk that contamination could lead to pollution of the River Mole, which in turn could affect our sources at Leatherhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The EA has required additional protection against the risk in the short term, but longer term the risks are not so well understood. However well-designed, there is a risk of failure at some time in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public confidence is also dropping in two of the companies responsible for the drilling to foot the bill should a clean up of this scale be necessary. With over £50m wiped off UKOG’s share price recently due to possible formation damage from acid at Broadford Bridge oil well in Sussex and Europa’s share price going steadily down by over 66% in 5yrs, from over 12p in April 2013 to 3.85p on Wed 21st Feb, campaigners against the drilling fear this could end up costing the tax payer a lot more than they bargained for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information, comment or to arrange a photo call, please contact Serena Billinghurst on 07727 123 874 or email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:serena@hwebber.co.uk&quot;&gt;serena@hwebber.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sign the petition please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://you.38degrees.org.uk/petitions/protect-leith-hill-in-surrey-from-the-risk-of-water-contamination-from-planned-oil-drilling-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://you.38degrees.org.uk/petitions/protect-leith-hill-in-surrey-from-the-risk-of-water-contamination-from-planned-oil-drilling-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft environmental permit and supporting documents &lt;a href=&quot;https://consult.environment-agency.gov.uk/psc/rh6-6hn-europa-oil-and-gas-limited/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can be viewed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EA's invitation to the 1st March public meeting at Dorking &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/residents-invited-to-holmwood-drilling-site-drop-in-event&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Petition against risk to water supply nears 100,000 signatures</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Environment Agency Permit Consultation - Open Now!!</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/20/ea-consultation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Environment Agency Permit Consultation - Open Now!!" /><published>2018-02-20T21:12:35+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-20T21:12:35+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/20/ea-consultation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/20/ea-consultation/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;environment-agency-consultation&quot;&gt;Environment Agency Consultation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Environment Agency have opened a public consultation on the draft environmental permit they are now minded to issue following the original public consultation held in May 2017 regarding Europa’s permit application. The consultation is open until 29th March 2018. We have now produced a submission guidance document with &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/03/23/ea-guidance/&quot;&gt;information on how to submit your comments which you can find here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Environment Agency Consultation</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Acidisation Infosheet</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/15/acidisation-infosheet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acidisation Infosheet" /><published>2018-02-15T22:11:23+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T22:11:23+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/15/acidisation-infosheet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/02/15/acidisation-infosheet/">&lt;h2&gt;Acidisation and Tight Oil&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should oil exist under the Weald basin at all, oil speculators have stated that it will be in the form of &quot;tight oil&quot; deposits - which are locked into the rock formations rather than being conventional free-flowing reservoirs. Confusingly however, they also state they do not intend to conduct fracking to access it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Weald Action Group have produced an excellent, informative leaflet which addresses this apparent contradiction, explaining how tight oil deposits can also be exploited using highly corrosive acids to dissolve the rock instead of hydraulic fracturing (&quot;fracking&quot;). You can &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/acidisation-infosheet.pdf&quot;&gt;download it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Acidisation and Tight Oil</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Traffic Management Plan 2017/0212 - Email Template</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/01/20/traffic-management-plan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Traffic Management Plan 2017/0212 - Email Template" /><published>2018-01-20T23:21:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-20T23:21:04+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/01/20/traffic-management-plan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2018/01/20/traffic-management-plan/">&lt;h2&gt;New Traffic Management Plan - Email Template&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi all, our &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/tmp-0212.pdf&quot;&gt;email template for the new Traffic Management Plan is now available here&lt;/a&gt;. The application can be viewed at Surrey Country Council's &lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0212&quot;&gt;planning portal&lt;/a&gt; and is now open for public consultation until Feb 7th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;N.B.&lt;/b&gt; this is a brand new application (because Europa are taking the previous one to appeal) which means that we please need EVERYONE to resubmit all their comments!! Surrey County Council have advised that we are effectively starting again with a clean slate, so all our previous objections need to go in again (providing they are still relevant) and we'll also get the chance to speak again when this proposal goes before the planning committee. Remember to include the new application number 2017/0212 plus your name and &lt;b&gt;full postal address&lt;/b&gt; in your response. Thank you!!

&lt;h2&gt;How Do I Submit Comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the above template, you can email comments with your name and full postal address to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: mwcd@surreycc.gov.uk&quot;&gt; mwcd@surreycc.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt; quoting: SCC Ref 2017/0212 or you can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0212&quot;&gt;comment online here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When Does The Consultation Close?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation closes on Feb 7th. If for some reason you absolutely can't submit comments by that date then there is still some value in submitting late. Although the council are not obliged to take account of comments received outside the formal consultation period, they may to choose to do so until shortly before the application goes to committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">New Traffic Management Plan - Email Template</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Traffic Management Plan Revisions - Email Template</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/10/01/tmp-revisions-email-template/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traffic Management Plan Revisions - Email Template" /><published>2017-10-01T22:11:04+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-01T22:11:04+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/10/01/tmp-revisions-email-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/10/01/tmp-revisions-email-template/">&lt;h2&gt;Latest Revisions to Traffic Management Plan - Email Template&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An email template for submitting comments concerning the latest revisions to the traffic management plan is &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/tmp-revisions.pdf&quot;&gt;now available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Latest Revisions to Traffic Management Plan - Email Template</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">T-Shirts are here!</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/09/26/t-shirts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T-Shirts are here!" /><published>2017-09-26T22:14:04+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-26T22:14:04+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/09/26/t-shirts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/09/26/t-shirts/">&lt;p&gt;Voice For Leith Hill t-shirts are now available to buy!!! Available in a range of M/F/kids sizes and styles: £10 for adults, £5 for kids. All proceeds go towards campaign fundraising. You can pick them up from the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.broccolimarketing.com/&quot;&gt;Broccoli Marketing&lt;/a&gt; on North Street, Dorking between 11am and 3pm daily, or else email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@voiceforleithhill.co.uk&quot;&gt;info@voiceforleithhill.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; to arrange payment/pickup. A big thanks to everyone who has helped make this happen!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/t-shirts.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Voice For Leith Hill t-shirts are now available to buy!!! Available in a range of M/F/kids sizes and styles: £10 for adults, £5 for kids. All proceeds go towards campaign fundraising. You can pick them up from the wonderful Broccoli Marketing on North Street, Dorking between 11am and 3pm daily, or else email info@voiceforleithhill.co.uk to arrange payment/pickup. A big thanks to everyone who has helped make this happen!!</summary></entry></feed>