<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-09-17T11:48:36+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/</id><title>A Voice For Leith Hill</title><subtitle>Non-party political community group committed to raising awareness and protesting against the proposed oil exploration at Leith Hill</subtitle><entry><title>Trees In The Early Morning</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trees In The Early Morning" /><published>2016-09-02T08:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T08:10:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;For me, trees have always been the most penetrating preachers. I revere them when they live in tribes and families, in forests and groves. And even more I revere them when they stand alone. They are like lonely persons. Not like hermits who have stolen away out of some weakness, but like great, solitary men, like Beethoven and Nietzsche. In their highest boughs the world rustles, their roots rest in infinity; but they do not lose themselves there, they struggle with all the force of their lives for one thing only: to fulfil themselves according to their own laws, to build up their own form, to represent themselves. Nothing is holier, nothing is more exemplary than a beautiful, strong tree. When a tree is cut down and reveals its naked death-wound to the sun, one can read its whole history in the luminous, inscribed disk of its trunk: in the rings of its years, its scars, all the struggle, all the suffering, all the sickness, all the happiness and prosperity stand truly written, the narrow years and the luxurious years, the attacks withstood, the storms endured. And every young farmboy knows that the hardest and noblest wood has the narrowest rings, that high on the mountains and in continuing danger the most indestructible, the strongest, the ideal trees grow.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Trees are sanctuaries. Whoever knows how to speak to them, whoever knows how to listen to them, can learn the truth. They do not preach learning and precepts, they preach, undeterred by particulars, the ancient law of life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A tree says: A kernel is hidden in me, a spark, a thought, I am life from eternal life. The attempt and the risk that the eternal mother took with me is unique, unique the form and veins of my skin, unique the smallest play of leaves in my branches and the smallest scar on my bark. I was made to form and reveal the eternal in my smallest special detail.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A tree says: My strength is trust. I know nothing about my fathers, I know nothing about the thousand children that every year spring out of me. I live out the secret of my seed to the very end, and I care for nothing else. I trust that God is in me. I trust that my labor is holy. Out of this trust I live.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When we are stricken and cannot bear our lives any longer, then a tree has something to say to us: Be still! Be still! Look at me! Life is not easy, life is not difficult. Those are childish thoughts. Let God speak within you, and your thoughts will grow silent. You are anxious because your path leads away from mother and home. But every step and every day lead you back again to the mother. Home is neither here nor there. Home is within you, or home is nowhere at all.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A longing to wander tears my heart when I hear trees rustling in the wind at evening. If one listens to them silently for a long time, this longing reveals its kernel, its meaning. It is not so much a matter of escaping from one&#39;s suffering, though it may seem to be so. It is a longing for home, for a memory of the mother, for new metaphors for life. It leads home. Every path leads homeward, every step is birth, every step is death, every grave is mother.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So the tree rustles in the evening, when we stand uneasy before our own childish thoughts: Trees have long thoughts, long-breathing and restful, just as they have longer lives than ours. They are wiser than we are, as long as we do not listen to them. But when we have learned how to listen to trees, then the brevity and the quickness and the childlike hastiness of our thoughts achieve an incomparable joy. Whoever has learned how to listen to trees no longer wants to be a tree. He wants to be nothing except what he is. That is home. That is happiness.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

- Herman Hesse, Wandering (1915)

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the glorious trees which are most at risk of direct damage at the proposed drilling site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040312-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040311-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040306-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040305-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040304-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary>&quot;For me, trees have always been the most penetrating preachers. I revere them when they live in tribes and families, in forests and groves. And even more I revere them when they stand alone. They are like lonely persons. Not like hermits who have stolen away out of some weakness, but like great, solitary men, like Beethoven and Nietzsche. In their highest boughs the world rustles, their roots rest in infinity; but they do not lose themselves there, they struggle with all the force of their lives for one thing only: to fulfil themselves according to their own laws, to build up their own form, to represent themselves. Nothing is holier, nothing is more exemplary than a beautiful, strong tree. When a tree is cut down and reveals its naked death-wound to the sun, one can read its whole history in the luminous, inscribed disk of its trunk: in the rings of its years, its scars, all the struggle, all the suffering, all the sickness, all the happiness and prosperity stand truly written, the narrow years and the luxurious years, the attacks withstood, the storms endured. And every young farmboy knows that the hardest and noblest wood has the narrowest rings, that high on the mountains and in continuing danger the most indestructible, the strongest, the ideal trees grow.

Trees are sanctuaries. Whoever knows how to speak to them, whoever knows how to listen to them, can learn the truth. They do not preach learning and precepts, they preach, undeterred by particulars, the ancient law of life.

A tree says: A kernel is hidden in me, a spark, a thought, I am life from eternal life. The attempt and the risk that the eternal mother took with me is unique, unique the form and veins of my skin, unique the smallest play of leaves in my branches and the smallest scar on my bark. I was made to form and reveal the eternal in my smallest special detail.

A tree says: My strength is trust. I know nothing about my fathers, I know nothing about the thousand children that every year spring out of me. I live out the secret of my seed to the very end, and I care for nothing else. I trust that God is in me. I trust that my labor is holy. Out of this trust I live.

When we are stricken and cannot bear our lives any longer, then a tree has something to say to us: Be still! Be still! Look at me! Life is not easy, life is not difficult. Those are childish thoughts. Let God speak within you, and your thoughts will grow silent. You are anxious because your path leads away from mother and home. But every step and every day lead you back again to the mother. Home is neither here nor there. Home is within you, or home is nowhere at all.

A longing to wander tears my heart when I hear trees rustling in the wind at evening. If one listens to them silently for a long time, this longing reveals its kernel, its meaning. It is not so much a matter of escaping from one&#39;s suffering, though it may seem to be so. It is a longing for home, for a memory of the mother, for new metaphors for life. It leads home. Every path leads homeward, every step is birth, every step is death, every grave is mother.

So the tree rustles in the evening, when we stand uneasy before our own childish thoughts: Trees have long thoughts, long-breathing and restful, just as they have longer lives than ours. They are wiser than we are, as long as we do not listen to them. But when we have learned how to listen to trees, then the brevity and the quickness and the childlike hastiness of our thoughts achieve an incomparable joy. Whoever has learned how to listen to trees no longer wants to be a tree. He wants to be nothing except what he is. That is home. That is happiness.&quot;</summary></entry><entry><title>Leith Hill Place - Short Film</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leith Hill Place - Short Film" /><published>2016-08-14T00:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-14T00:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place/">&lt;div id=&quot;avplayer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  // Load the IFrame Player API code asynchronously.
  var tag = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);
  tag.src = &quot;https://www.youtube.com/player_api&quot;;
  var firstScriptTag = document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;script&#39;)[0];
  firstScriptTag.parentNode.insertBefore(tag, firstScriptTag);

  // Replace the &#39;ytplayer&#39; element with an &lt;iframe&gt; and
  // YouTube player after the API code downloads.
  var player;
  function onYouTubePlayerAPIReady() {
    player = new YT.Player(&#39;avplayer&#39;, {
      height: &#39;315&#39;,
      width: &#39;560&#39;,
      videoId: &#39;j7m4eS60Dnk&#39;
    });
  }
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Leith Hill Place</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leith Hill Place" /><published>2016-07-21T22:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-21T22:20:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/VFLH-NT-VERSION14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bring a Picnic Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>A Voice For Leith Hill</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/01/about-v4lh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Voice For Leith Hill" /><published>2016-07-01T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-01T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/01/about-v4lh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/01/about-v4lh/">&lt;p&gt;A Voice For Leith Hill (AVFLH) are a group of local artists, musicians and environmentalists who joined together to protest peacefully and raise awareness concerning the planned oil drilling on Leith Hill due to start later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campaign originated at a picnic event on the planned drilling site in Bury Hill Woods last autumn, where participants decided on a plan of peaceful action through a series of art exhibitions and concerts aimed at raising awareness about the pending senseless destruction of one of the South of England&#39;s most beautiful and cherished natural habitats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A travelling art exhibition celebrating the beauty of Leith Hill and highlighting the wildlife under threat commenced at The Star, Dorking in January 2016 where it remained until end of March. There was a successful opening event with local bands, guest speakers and many signatures added to our petition. During this time AVFLH also ran a stall in Dorking High Street with a big live street art demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April the exhibition was warmly welcomed at the newly refurbished Plough Inn, Coldharbour with a jam-packed opening event including the village bands, A Voice For Leith Hill musicians and speakers, a speech from the LHAG chairman and a talk about the ecology under threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 6th August to 30th October 2016, the exhibition will then be moving to Leith Hill Place. On Saturday 13th August from 12pm there will be a family launch event including live music, art activities, animal face painting and further talks. All are welcome. Please bring a picnic or else cream teas will be available in the house.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary>A Voice For Leith Hill (AVFLH) are a group of local artists, musicians and environmentalists who joined together to protest peacefully and raise awareness concerning the planned oil drilling on Leith Hill due to start later this year.</summary></entry></feed>
