<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-12T08:51:16+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/</id><title type="html">A Voice For Leith Hill</title><subtitle>Non-party political community group committed to raising awareness and protesting against the proposed oil exploration at Leith Hill</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Traffic Management Plan - Email Template</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/06/17/traffic-management-email-template/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traffic Management Plan - Email Template" /><published>2017-06-17T10:11:04+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-17T10:11:04+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/06/17/traffic-management-email-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/06/17/traffic-management-email-template/">&lt;h2&gt;Email Template&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An email template for submitting comments to the traffic management planning application is &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/TrafficManagementEmailTemplate.docx&quot;&gt;now available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Email Template</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Traffic Management Plan</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/06/16/traffic-management-plan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traffic Management Plan" /><published>2017-06-16T20:11:04+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-16T20:11:04+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/06/16/traffic-management-plan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/06/16/traffic-management-plan/">&lt;h2&gt;Key Points&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Europa's traffic management planning application has now been published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0027&quot;&gt;Surrey Country Council's planning portal&lt;/a&gt; and is open for public consultation. Key points include:
  &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Between 700 and 1100+ HGV movements from A24, up Flint Hill, into Knoll Road and up Coldharbour Lane: exact volumes depend on whether HGV carriageways can be built with aluminium or if they require a stone base.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Major resulting impacts to &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;traffic&lt;/span&gt; flows across Dorking, which currently struggle to handle existing volumes and are highly prone to gridlock from even minor disruptions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HGV convoy holding bay in Knoll Road, which as a residential road and main school route is completely unsuitable.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A further stone delivery HGV holding bay will be in Ryka's car park at Box Hill, as a feeder via A24 and Flint Hill into the Knoll Road holding bay.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Major and irreparable impact to the trees, banks and road surface of Coldharbour Lane, which is a historic sunken lane currently signposted as unsuitable for HGVs. It is absolutely unsuitable for 60 tonne crane carriers, 50 tonne drilling rig transporters and flatbeds carrying earth-moving machinery.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The proposal to identify drilling rig transporter passing places in Coldharbour Lane to reduce local transport delays is nonsensical: there aren't any places where a car could pass a 50 tonne drilling rig in transit on Coldharbour Lane.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The disruptions are likely to cause increased use of other backroads such as Logmore Lane, resulting in secondary damage there also.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Increased risk to road users: Europa's own &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;traffic&lt;/span&gt; survey admits there is a high risk to cyclists of a serious accident on Coldharbour Lane on Saturday mornings.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Road closures, delays and blockages are likely to endanger any residents who need emergency services.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The road condition survey &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/span&gt; includes no details about temporary damage assessments such as that from soil deposits which pose a major risk to cyclists and motorbikes, or ice, diesel spills or wet leaves which might impact the traction of HGVs on the steepest sections of Coldharbour Lane during winter months.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No Environmental Impact Assessment has been conducted for the &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Traffic&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Management&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Plan&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/span&gt; is effectively just an addendum to the &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;traffic&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;management&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/span&gt; from 2014 which has already been rejected as completely unsuitable by the &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;planning&lt;/span&gt; authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How Do I Submit Comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/plancomment.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0027&quot;&gt;comment online here&lt;/a&gt; or else email comments with your name and full postal address to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: mwcd@surreycc.gov.uk&quot;&gt; mwcd@surreycc.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt; quoting: SCC Ref 2017/0027.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When Does The Consultation Close?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation closes on 21st June. It is still worth submitting if you miss this date, as although the council are not obliged to take account of comments received outside this formal consultation period they will normally do so up to the date a decision is made.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Key Points</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EA Consultation - [update: Now Closed]</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/05/06/ea-consultation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EA Consultation - [update: Now Closed]" /><published>2017-05-06T22:12:04+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-06T22:12:04+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/05/06/ea-consultation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/05/06/ea-consultation/">&lt;h2&gt;How Do I Reply?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://consult.environment-agency.gov.uk/psc/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-and-gas-limited/consultation/intro/&quot;&gt;reply online here&lt;/a&gt; in a very simple process that just requires you to submit your name, email address and comments. Alternatively you can send an email a email with subject Application No: EPR/YP3735YK/A001 to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pscpublicresponse@environment-agency.gov.uk&quot;&gt;pscpublicresponse@environment-agency.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When Does The Consultation Close?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation closes on 16th May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Do You Have A Summary Of The Key Issues?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an excellent summary on &lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2017/04/06/consultation-opens-on-permit-applications-for-europas-leith-hill-drilling-site/&quot;&gt;Drill Or Drop here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition you may want to consider some of the following points. &lt;b&gt;N.B.&lt;/b&gt; To get your voice heard properly, it is much more effective to please makes sure you express the issues which concern you the most using your own words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Concerning Water Risk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EA’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.environment-agency.gov.uk/wiyby/wiybyController?topic=drinkingwater&amp;amp;layerGroups=default&amp;amp;lang=_e&amp;amp;ep=map&amp;amp;scale=4&amp;amp;x=357682.99999999994&amp;amp;y=355133.99999999994#x=516989&amp;amp;y=144076&amp;amp;lg=2,3,10,&amp;amp;scale=7&quot;&gt;water safeguard zone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://environment.data.gov.uk/catchment-planning/WaterBody/GB106039017580&quot;&gt;water catchment area maps&lt;/a&gt; show that the proposed drilling site is located directly next to a Surface Water Safeguard Zone and in the catchment area of the Pipp Brook directly upstream of a Groundwater Safeguard Zone. The potential impact of this location to the local drinking water supply has already been previously highlighted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-surrey-34930442&quot;&gt;Sutton and East Surrey Water.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the supplied Environmental Risk Assessment, the applicant identifies a number of Possible Sources of Accident with consequences of polluting the groundwater or surface water. They then claim that the overall risk is low providing the correct management techniques are followed. On this basis plus the related information supplied in their Waste Management Plan, they propose that they should be exempt from needing a groundwater permit. However:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if the probability of an accident is low providing the correct management techniques are followed, given the proximity of the water safeguard zones then the impact of any such incident will be very large. There is no way the overall risk can be classified as low as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No consideration is given to accidents relating to a failure to follow correct management techniques. What secondary measures are being implemented to reduce impact in the instance something does go wrong?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given this is exploratory drilling, what safeguards are being employed to mitigate any possibility of ‘accidental’ horizontal drilling from the drill pad on the edge of the water safeguard zones into the actual safeguard zone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no indication of linked and/or compound risks in the Risk Assessment. Clearly the risks are not all completely independent. How is the risk of a contamination incident increased by fire for example, which might lead to a seal failure and pipe rupture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The high/medium/low risk classification is a subjective oversimplification that is clearly being misapplied in this application: the argument put forwards in the generic risk assessment table that the groundwater risk should only be classified as medium because it is not as severe as the surface water risk is nonsensical. Both risks are obviously high, it is just that one is larger than the other. A more quantitative approach would have avoided such problems and enabled a much more accurate risk profile to be described.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only short-term risks resulting from failures of storage tanks or pipe ruptures are considered. What about the risks from well casing failures? There there have been many instances of boreholes failing and becoming conduits of water contamination (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1992/05/03/us/abandoned-oil-and-gas-wells-become-pollution-portals.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://shale.palwv.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/SPE-166142-PA-P2-copy.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://higherlogicdownload.s3.amazonaws.com/SPE/a77592d6-ec9a-43b1-b57b-c7275fb91cb0/UploadedImages/SPE%20Review/Review%202013/SPE%20Review%20March%202013%20-%20Web%20Version.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). In the longer term these represent a greater risk than storage tanks rupture, but they are not mentioned at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the water risks identified in the risk assessment are examples of low probability, high impact risks which are notoriously difficult to manage effectively. Generally, a strategy of prevention/avoidance is the only truly safe policy. Given the fact that this well is likely to have a very limited lifespan anyway due to the ever increasing threat from climate change (on which point, the glaring omission in the applicant’s Global Warming Potential section is the product they are actually drilling), and abandoning the well will then only increase the risk of future contamination incidents, the only reasonable and rationally defensible strategy is most obviously not to drill for oil in this location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Waste Management Plan, the applicant is requesting exemption from having to apply for groundwater permit on the basis that the quantity of the acidisation pollutant would be small. However, the applicant only specifies the volume of acid per foot. What is the total volume they will be using? Also what about the other chemicals such as the anti corrosives, surfactants and demulsifiers used in the acidisation process? These are also clearly contamination sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the limit of the applicant's liability insurance? Has the applicant sourced independent estimates of the clean-up costs of each risk identified in their Risk Assessment? Do any of these exceed their liability limit? In the instance that the applicant decided to cease trading following a contamindation incident, what insurances would remain in place and for how long?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. Concerning Waste Management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application uses the term ‘acid squeeze’. Assume this is in fact matrix acidisation, then the application should be amended to use standard industry terminology in the interests of clarity and transparency. Given the increasing regulation such techniques are being subjected to in other territories where they have not already been banned outright, this technique should not be allowed in the UK until a full impact assessment has been performed and regulatory guidance has been published.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to the spent hydrochloric acid solution once it has been used to clean out the geological fractures? How is this monitored, and how visible are the test results to the public?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hot oil will be pumped into the well to 'remove paraffin precipitates': What happens to the 'paraffin precipitates'? How is this monitored, and how visible are the test results to the public?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oil-containing drilling muds, Oil-containing rock cuttings: What happens to them? How is this monitored, and how visible are the test results to the public?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Hazardous run-off water: How is this monitored, and how visible are the test results to the public?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radioactive materials: 'radioactive materials' are not all unnatural. Many shales are naturally radioactive due to the potassium isotopes in clays, as well as adsorbed uranium, radium, polonium and thorium. How will the applicant handle the processing of any naturally occurring and equally hazardous radioactive materials discovered during the exploratory drilling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; 3. Concerning Local Authority Planning Permits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On page 4 of the Site Condition Report, the site footprint is stated as being 0.79 hectares. This is incorrect. The site is now in fact 1.01 hectares, as the applicant has extended the site footprint by 28% as part of a subsequent security fencing application that has been submitted to Surrey County Council. Ref: 2016/0170 http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0170&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On page 19 of Site Condition Report, the applicant claims that no baseline monitoring can be performed until the start of operations. This is incorrect: on 21st October last year they were granted planning permission to commence baseline testing: https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0151&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, the applicant has a farm-out deal for this site with Angus Energy who are currently contesting with Surrey County Council a possible breach of planning regulations at their Brockham site. No environmental permit should be granted until the outcome of that case in known, as a confirmed breach will significantly undermine the applicant’s claims to follow industry best practice on which much of its risk mitigation plan depends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">How Do I Reply? You can reply online here in a very simple process that just requires you to submit your name, email address and comments. Alternatively you can send an email a email with subject Application No: EPR/YP3735YK/A001 to pscpublicresponse@environment-agency.gov.uk</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EA Consultation Open - Let’s Get Writing!!</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/04/07/ea-consultation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EA Consultation Open - Let's Get Writing!!" /><published>2017-04-07T00:12:04+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:12:04+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/04/07/ea-consultation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/04/07/ea-consultation/">&lt;p&gt;Europa Oil and Gas have now submitted three applications to the Environment Agency, covering:
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exploratory onshore oil and gas operations (mining waste permit)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Oil storage&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Accumulation and safe disposal of radioactive substances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excellent summary of the key points has been posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://drillordrop.com/2017/04/06/consultation-opens-on-permit-applications-for-europas-leith-hill-drilling-site/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drill Or Drop&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further information on the environmental permit applications and how to take part in the consultation (which is running until 16 May 2017) please see the following links:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-gas-limited-environmental-permit-application-advertisement/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-gas-limited-environmental-permit-application-advertisement&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Europa's Environmental Permit Application&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://consult.environment-agency.gov.uk/psc/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-and-gas-limited/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Public Consultation on Europa's Environmental Permit Application&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
More general information about how the EA determines Environmental permit applications and the types of permit required to allow exploratory exploration for onshore oil and gas, can be found here:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/environmental-permitting-public-participation-statement&quot;&gt;Public Consultation and Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/onshore-oil-and-gas-exploration-and-extraction-environmental-permits&quot;&gt;Onshore oil and gas exploration and extraction: Environmental Permits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
If you have any further questions about the Environment Agency's role in the regulation of onshore oil and gas but not related specifically to these permit applications at Holmwood please contact us via kslenquiries@environment-agency.gov.uk
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Europa Oil and Gas have now submitted three applications to the Environment Agency, covering: Exploratory onshore oil and gas operations (mining waste permit) Oil storage Accumulation and safe disposal of radioactive substances An excellent summary of the key points has been posted on Drill Or Drop. For further information on the environmental permit applications and how to take part in the consultation (which is running until 16 May 2017) please see the following links: Europa's Environmental Permit Application Public Consultation on Europa's Environmental Permit Application More general information about how the EA determines Environmental permit applications and the types of permit required to allow exploratory exploration for onshore oil and gas, can be found here: Public Consultation and Participation Onshore oil and gas exploration and extraction: Environmental Permits If you have any further questions about the Environment Agency's role in the regulation of onshore oil and gas but not related specifically to these permit applications at Holmwood please contact us via kslenquiries@environment-agency.gov.uk</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Current Status and Timelines</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/02/timelines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Current Status and Timelines" /><published>2017-03-02T12:50:24+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-02T12:50:24+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/02/timelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/02/timelines/">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Surrey County Council refused permission for a planning application to explore for oil and gas at Leith Hill. The decision was appealed, and the subsequent public inquiry again rejected permission. That decision was then challenged in the High Court, which found favour with the applicant resulting in a second public inquiry. This unfortunately coincided with a change in the planning regulations, and as a result the government planning inspectorate decided to grant permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Government Planning Inspectorate&lt;/b&gt;'s decision (ref: APP/B3600/A/11/2166561) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://acp.planninginspectorate.gov.uk/ViewCase.aspx?caseid=2166561&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;hr class=&quot;spacer&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Environment Agency Permit Applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following application has now been submitted to the Environment Agency.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-gas-limited-environmental-permit-application-advertisement/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-gas-limited-environmental-permit-application-advertisement&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Europa's Environmental Permit Application&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://consult.environment-agency.gov.uk/psc/rh5-6hn-europa-oil-and-gas-limited/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Public Consultation on Europa's Environmental Permit Application (now closed)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;spacer&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Surrey County Council Planning Applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrey County Council planning application register is &lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planapplist.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of required submissions (some of which, e.g. traffic management plan, are still pending) can be found listed in the approval conditions of planning inspectorate's decision, linked above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there is one further fencing application relating to 2016/0151 below concerning the installation of security fencing around borehole testing areas which Surrey County Council has confirmed as permitted development. This means the proposal does not require public consultation. We are currently awaiting direction from the Secretary of State as to whether an Environmental Impact Assessment is still needed and whether the application should be called in as a full, standard application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Ref&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Action Required&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0027&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2017/0027&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Traffic Management Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Public Consultation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0024&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2017/0024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Traffic Survey&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Published traffic survey results&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0028&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2017/0028&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Noise monitoring plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202017/0001&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2017/0001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1.1 metre high reptile fence&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0232&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0232*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Perimeter security fencing (identical to 2016/0170, but now extended for 52 weeks)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Unconfirmed so far by SCC whether this will have a separate formal public consultation period. The Secretary of State has confirmed that a new Environmental Impact Assessment is needed for this application.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0194&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0194&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Landscape and Restoration Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Planning Committee 22/03/2017&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0193&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0193&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Pre and post development condition survey&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Planning Committee 22/02/2017&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0170&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0170*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Perimeter security fencing (see also 2016/0232 above)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Decision by Planning Committee: deferred from March 2017 meeting under guidance from Secretary of State that a new Environmental Impact Assessment is needed.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;TBD (attendance at planning hearing)&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0151&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0151&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Groundwater and Surface Water Baseline Quality and Monitoring&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Delegated Powers 21/10/2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0132&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0132&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Ecological Monitoring and Management Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Compulsory public consultation finished; pending decision by Delegated Powers&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Objections may still be submitted for consideration&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0104&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0104&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Light Management Plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Planning Committee 07/12/2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planning.surreycc.gov.uk/planappdisp.aspx?AppNo=SCC%20Ref%202016/0103&quot; class=&quot;submission&quot;&gt;2016/0103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Dust Suppression Scheme&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;approved&quot;&gt;Approved&lt;/em&gt; by Delegated Powers 08/12/2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* asterisked items denote new, additional planning applications rather than submissions concerning the fulfillment (or &quot;discharge&quot;) of the conditions previously specified by the planning inspectorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction In 2011, Surrey County Council refused permission for a planning application to explore for oil and gas at Leith Hill. The decision was appealed, and the subsequent public inquiry again rejected permission. That decision was then challenged in the High Court, which found favour with the applicant resulting in a second public inquiry. This unfortunately coincided with a change in the planning regulations, and as a result the government planning inspectorate decided to grant permission. The Government Planning Inspectorate's decision (ref: APP/B3600/A/11/2166561) is here. Environment Agency Permit Applications The following application has now been submitted to the Environment Agency. Europa's Environmental Permit Application Public Consultation on Europa's Environmental Permit Application (now closed) Surrey County Council Planning Applications Surrey County Council planning application register is here. The full list of required submissions (some of which, e.g. traffic management plan, are still pending) can be found listed in the approval conditions of planning inspectorate's decision, linked above. Also, there is one further fencing application relating to 2016/0151 below concerning the installation of security fencing around borehole testing areas which Surrey County Council has confirmed as permitted development. This means the proposal does not require public consultation. We are currently awaiting direction from the Secretary of State as to whether an Environmental Impact Assessment is still needed and whether the application should be called in as a full, standard application. Ref Title Status Action Required 2017/0027 Traffic Management Plan Public Consultation Yes 2017/0024 Traffic Survey Published traffic survey results No 2017/0028 Noise monitoring plan Objections may still be submitted for consideration Yes 2017/0001 1.1 metre high reptile fence Objections may still be submitted for consideration Yes 2016/0232* Perimeter security fencing (identical to 2016/0170, but now extended for 52 weeks) Unconfirmed so far by SCC whether this will have a separate formal public consultation period. The Secretary of State has confirmed that a new Environmental Impact Assessment is needed for this application. Objections may still be submitted for consideration 2016/0194 Landscape and Restoration Plan Approved by Planning Committee 22/03/2017 2016/0193 Pre and post development condition survey Approved by Planning Committee 22/02/2017 2016/0170* Perimeter security fencing (see also 2016/0232 above) Decision by Planning Committee: deferred from March 2017 meeting under guidance from Secretary of State that a new Environmental Impact Assessment is needed. TBD (attendance at planning hearing) 2016/0151 Groundwater and Surface Water Baseline Quality and Monitoring Approved by Delegated Powers 21/10/2016 2016/0132 Ecological Monitoring and Management Plan Compulsory public consultation finished; pending decision by Delegated Powers Objections may still be submitted for consideration 2016/0104 Light Management Plan Approved by Planning Committee 07/12/2016 2016/0103 Dust Suppression Scheme Approved by Delegated Powers 08/12/2016 * asterisked items denote new, additional planning applications rather than submissions concerning the fulfillment (or &quot;discharge&quot;) of the conditions previously specified by the planning inspectorate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High Street Stall - 4th March</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/01/stall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Street Stall - 4th March" /><published>2017-03-01T11:12:04+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-01T11:12:04+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/01/stall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2017/03/01/stall/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/stall.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're going to be out on the high street again this Saturday morning (4th March, from 9:30am) at our usual spot outside Oxfam. Please drop by to say hello, pick up a leaflet, or to find out more about the current status of the campaign! Hope to see you there...&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Surrey Slings Leith Hill Celebration Walk</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/12/03/leith-hill-walk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surrey Slings Leith Hill Celebration Walk" /><published>2016-12-03T00:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-03T00:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/12/03/leith-hill-walk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/12/03/leith-hill-walk/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/surrey-slings-walk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surrey Slings Leith Hill Celebration Walk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Meeting places for the Leith Hill Celebration Walk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St Joseph's Church, Falkland Grove, Dorking, RH4 3DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Cyclists meeting at 10.30am to cycle up Coldharbour Lane and walk to the tower.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starveall Car Park, Leith Hill Rd, Dorking, RH5 6LU:&lt;/strong&gt; A family friendly route, with walkers meeting at 10.15am and departing at 10.30am. It is suitable for small children, buggies and older people looking for a gentle walk.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday Street, Dorking, RH5 6JR:&lt;/strong&gt; Walkers are meeting at 10.30am for a 10.45am start. The route is suitable for adults and capable walkers.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windy Gap Car Park, Abinger Road, Dorking, RH5 6LX:&lt;/strong&gt; A steep ascent to the tower that is expected to take around 40 minutes to complete.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landslip Car Park, Abinger Road, Dorking, RH5 6HG:&lt;/strong&gt; A short, steep climb to the top of the hill that should take around 45 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rhodedenron Wood Car Park, Dorking, RH5 6LU:&lt;/strong&gt; A longer route from Leith Hill Place's car park with some steep sections.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The Facebook event details are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/333484617025339/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trees In The Early Morning</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trees In The Early Morning" /><published>2016-09-02T08:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T08:10:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/09/02/trees/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;For me, trees have always been the most penetrating preachers. I revere them when they live in tribes and families, in forests and groves. And even more I revere them when they stand alone. They are like lonely persons. Not like hermits who have stolen away out of some weakness, but like great, solitary men, like Beethoven and Nietzsche. In their highest boughs the world rustles, their roots rest in infinity; but they do not lose themselves there, they struggle with all the force of their lives for one thing only: to fulfil themselves according to their own laws, to build up their own form, to represent themselves. Nothing is holier, nothing is more exemplary than a beautiful, strong tree. When a tree is cut down and reveals its naked death-wound to the sun, one can read its whole history in the luminous, inscribed disk of its trunk: in the rings of its years, its scars, all the struggle, all the suffering, all the sickness, all the happiness and prosperity stand truly written, the narrow years and the luxurious years, the attacks withstood, the storms endured. And every young farmboy knows that the hardest and noblest wood has the narrowest rings, that high on the mountains and in continuing danger the most indestructible, the strongest, the ideal trees grow.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Trees are sanctuaries. Whoever knows how to speak to them, whoever knows how to listen to them, can learn the truth. They do not preach learning and precepts, they preach, undeterred by particulars, the ancient law of life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A tree says: A kernel is hidden in me, a spark, a thought, I am life from eternal life. The attempt and the risk that the eternal mother took with me is unique, unique the form and veins of my skin, unique the smallest play of leaves in my branches and the smallest scar on my bark. I was made to form and reveal the eternal in my smallest special detail.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A tree says: My strength is trust. I know nothing about my fathers, I know nothing about the thousand children that every year spring out of me. I live out the secret of my seed to the very end, and I care for nothing else. I trust that God is in me. I trust that my labor is holy. Out of this trust I live.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When we are stricken and cannot bear our lives any longer, then a tree has something to say to us: Be still! Be still! Look at me! Life is not easy, life is not difficult. Those are childish thoughts. Let God speak within you, and your thoughts will grow silent. You are anxious because your path leads away from mother and home. But every step and every day lead you back again to the mother. Home is neither here nor there. Home is within you, or home is nowhere at all.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A longing to wander tears my heart when I hear trees rustling in the wind at evening. If one listens to them silently for a long time, this longing reveals its kernel, its meaning. It is not so much a matter of escaping from one's suffering, though it may seem to be so. It is a longing for home, for a memory of the mother, for new metaphors for life. It leads home. Every path leads homeward, every step is birth, every step is death, every grave is mother.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So the tree rustles in the evening, when we stand uneasy before our own childish thoughts: Trees have long thoughts, long-breathing and restful, just as they have longer lives than ours. They are wiser than we are, as long as we do not listen to them. But when we have learned how to listen to trees, then the brevity and the quickness and the childlike hastiness of our thoughts achieve an incomparable joy. Whoever has learned how to listen to trees no longer wants to be a tree. He wants to be nothing except what he is. That is home. That is happiness.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

- Herman Hesse, Wandering (1915)

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the glorious trees which are most at risk of direct damage at the proposed drilling site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040312-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040311-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040306-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040305-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/P1040304-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html">&quot;For me, trees have always been the most penetrating preachers. I revere them when they live in tribes and families, in forests and groves. And even more I revere them when they stand alone. They are like lonely persons. Not like hermits who have stolen away out of some weakness, but like great, solitary men, like Beethoven and Nietzsche. In their highest boughs the world rustles, their roots rest in infinity; but they do not lose themselves there, they struggle with all the force of their lives for one thing only: to fulfil themselves according to their own laws, to build up their own form, to represent themselves. Nothing is holier, nothing is more exemplary than a beautiful, strong tree. When a tree is cut down and reveals its naked death-wound to the sun, one can read its whole history in the luminous, inscribed disk of its trunk: in the rings of its years, its scars, all the struggle, all the suffering, all the sickness, all the happiness and prosperity stand truly written, the narrow years and the luxurious years, the attacks withstood, the storms endured. And every young farmboy knows that the hardest and noblest wood has the narrowest rings, that high on the mountains and in continuing danger the most indestructible, the strongest, the ideal trees grow. Trees are sanctuaries. Whoever knows how to speak to them, whoever knows how to listen to them, can learn the truth. They do not preach learning and precepts, they preach, undeterred by particulars, the ancient law of life. A tree says: A kernel is hidden in me, a spark, a thought, I am life from eternal life. The attempt and the risk that the eternal mother took with me is unique, unique the form and veins of my skin, unique the smallest play of leaves in my branches and the smallest scar on my bark. I was made to form and reveal the eternal in my smallest special detail. A tree says: My strength is trust. I know nothing about my fathers, I know nothing about the thousand children that every year spring out of me. I live out the secret of my seed to the very end, and I care for nothing else. I trust that God is in me. I trust that my labor is holy. Out of this trust I live. When we are stricken and cannot bear our lives any longer, then a tree has something to say to us: Be still! Be still! Look at me! Life is not easy, life is not difficult. Those are childish thoughts. Let God speak within you, and your thoughts will grow silent. You are anxious because your path leads away from mother and home. But every step and every day lead you back again to the mother. Home is neither here nor there. Home is within you, or home is nowhere at all. A longing to wander tears my heart when I hear trees rustling in the wind at evening. If one listens to them silently for a long time, this longing reveals its kernel, its meaning. It is not so much a matter of escaping from one's suffering, though it may seem to be so. It is a longing for home, for a memory of the mother, for new metaphors for life. It leads home. Every path leads homeward, every step is birth, every step is death, every grave is mother. So the tree rustles in the evening, when we stand uneasy before our own childish thoughts: Trees have long thoughts, long-breathing and restful, just as they have longer lives than ours. They are wiser than we are, as long as we do not listen to them. But when we have learned how to listen to trees, then the brevity and the quickness and the childlike hastiness of our thoughts achieve an incomparable joy. Whoever has learned how to listen to trees no longer wants to be a tree. He wants to be nothing except what he is. That is home. That is happiness.&quot;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leith Hill Place - Short Film</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leith Hill Place - Short Film" /><published>2016-08-14T00:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-14T00:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/08/14/leith-hill-place/">&lt;div id=&quot;avplayer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  // Load the IFrame Player API code asynchronously.
  var tag = document.createElement('script');
  tag.src = &quot;https://www.youtube.com/player_api&quot;;
  var firstScriptTag = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0];
  firstScriptTag.parentNode.insertBefore(tag, firstScriptTag);

  // Replace the 'ytplayer' element with an &lt;iframe&gt; and
  // YouTube player after the API code downloads.
  var player;
  function onYouTubePlayerAPIReady() {
    player = new YT.Player('avplayer', {
      height: '315',
      width: '560',
      videoId: 'j7m4eS60Dnk'
    });
  }
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leith Hill Place</title><link href="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leith Hill Place" /><published>2016-07-21T22:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-21T22:20:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.voiceforleithhill.co.uk/2016/07/21/leith-hill-place-picnic-day/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pics/VFLH-NT-VERSION14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bring a Picnic Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Voice for Leith Hill</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>